<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Krossovochkin</title>
    <link>https://krossovochkin.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Krossovochkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 Vasya Drobushkov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://krossovochkin.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Nitpicker&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2020_10_14_kotlin_nitpickers_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2020_10_14_kotlin_nitpickers_guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Code review is an essential tool for a development team, which helps ensure high-quality standards of code. While reviewing others&amp;rsquo; code one might find bugs, design issues, and so on. One another part of reviewing is getting used to the codebase and following team&amp;rsquo;s code style for better maintenance. Though it is pretty cool in theory, in practice team might face few issues, one of which is nitpicking. When review is bloated with dozens of similar comments related to e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2020_03_19_unit_testing_best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2020_03_19_unit_testing_best_practices/</guid>
      <description>Source

Disclaimer: This is a set of things I consider very useful when writing unit tests. I call them best practices because they allow me to write good, quality tests that are easier to read, more maintainable, and better describe business needs.
These points might be subjective, you might have other opinions or have more items. That’s fine. Do not hesitate to put your opinions in the comments.
Tests in the Development Process Tests are very important in the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Программирование и музыка</title>
      <link>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2018_06_24_programming_and_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://krossovochkin.github.io/posts/2018_06_24_programming_and_music/</guid>
      <description>Предисловие Наушники — лучший друг разработчика (спасибо открытым пространствам и людям вокруг). Шум и разговоры отвлекают от работы и не дают сосредоточиться. Решением являются отдельные комнаты для небольших команд (что встречается редко и все равно не является стопроцентным, потому что отвлекать может и просто клацание коллегами по клавиатуре) либо наушники плюс музыка в них. Также у музыки на работе есть и другие преимущества. Например, она может выступать в роли якоря.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>