<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coroutines on Vasya Drobushkov</title>
    <link>https://krossovochkin.com/tags/coroutines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coroutines on Vasya Drobushkov</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://krossovochkin.com/tags/coroutines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Coroutines Cancellation and Exception Handling</title>
      <link>https://krossovochkin.com/posts/2025_01_11_kotlin_coroutines_cancellation_and_exception_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krossovochkin.com/posts/2025_01_11_kotlin_coroutines_cancellation_and_exception_handling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cancellation and exception handling in coroutines is by far the most complex thing I&amp;rsquo;ve faced during my entire career. These two things are so complicated that I sometimes ask myself how people are using such a difficult-to-use framework. I read all the possible docs that I found, many different articles, video courses, and even tried to look at the code - and still, I feel that my understanding of this topic is quite bad.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When reading articles, I often thought that their structure was not good and that things were not clarified in a reasonable way. Usually, articles are just a collection of examples that show how certain combinations of suspending functions or coroutine builders will work. Learning by examples is good, but they should help with understanding core concepts so that all other situations are easy to relate to what was learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JUnit Coroutines Runner</title>
      <link>https://krossovochkin.com/posts/2021_07_10_junit_coroutines_runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krossovochkin.com/posts/2021_07_10_junit_coroutines_runner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently while writing tests for kotlin code with coroutines I found one annoying thing: almost all the tests start with &lt;code&gt;runBlockingTest&lt;/code&gt;. Typing the same stuff repeatedly is something we can&amp;rsquo;t accept! So, I decided to think about how to improve this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer. Yes, this is an example of how to spend few hours to optimize some task that requires you 2 seconds to complete each time. Even on a scale of hundreds of usages such optimization most likely won&amp;rsquo;t pay your time back. But it is always fun to do some weird things even if you understand that they are stupid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
